<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE entity PUBLIC "-//UC Berkeley//DTD MoML 1//EN"
    "http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/xml/dtd/MoML_1.dtd">
<entity name="MultipleInstanceWorkflow" class="ptolemy.actor.TypedCompositeActor">
    <property name="_createdBy" class="ptolemy.kernel.attributes.VersionAttribute" value="11.0.devel">
    </property>
    <property name="_windowProperties" class="ptolemy.actor.gui.WindowPropertiesAttribute" value="{bounds={0, 22, 1073, 810}, maximized=false}">
    </property>
    <property name="_vergilSize" class="ptolemy.actor.gui.SizeAttribute" value="[732, 657]">
    </property>
    <property name="_vergilZoomFactor" class="ptolemy.data.expr.ExpertParameter" value="1.0">
    </property>
    <property name="_vergilCenter" class="ptolemy.data.expr.ExpertParameter" value="{300.0, 340.5}">
    </property>
    <property name="PN Director" class="ptolemy.domains.pn.kernel.PNDirector">
        <property name="initialQueueCapacity" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="1">
        </property>
        <property name="maximumQueueCapacity" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="65536">
        </property>
<property name="KeplerDocumentation" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.KeplerDocumentationAttribute">
<property name="description" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="author" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Mudit Goel, Edward A. Lee, Xiaowen Xin</configure></property>
<property name="version" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="userLevelDocumentation" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>&#10;&lt;p&gt;PN Directors are natural candidates for managing workflows that require parallel processing on distributed computing systems. PN workflows are powerful because they have few restrictions. On the other hand, they can be very inefficient.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The Process Network (PN) Director is similar to the SDF Director in that it does not have a notion of time. However, unlike the SDF Director, the PN Director does not statically calculate firing schedules. Instead, a PN workflow is driven by data availability: tokens are created on output ports whenever input tokens are available and the outputs can be calculated. Output tokens are passed to connected actors, where they are held in a buffer until that next actor collects all required inputs and can fire. The PN Director finishes executing a workflow only when there are no new data token sources anywhere in the workflow. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The same execution process that gives the PN Director its flexibility can also lead to some unexpected results: workflows may refuse to automatically terminate because tokens are always generated and available to downstream actors, for example. If one actor fires at a much higher rate than another, a downstream actor's memory buffer may overflow, causing workflow execution to fail.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;</configure></property>
<property name="prop:initialQueueCapacity" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The initial size of the queues for each communication channel. The value is an integer that defaults to 1. This is an advanced parameter that can usually be left at its  default value.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:maximumQueueCapacity" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The maximum size of the queues for each communication channel. The value is an integer that defaults to 65536. To specify unbounded queues, set the value to 0. This is an advanced parameter that can usually be left at its  default value.</configure></property>
</property>        <property name="entityId" class="org.kepler.moml.NamedObjId" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:director:2:1">
        </property>
        <property name="class" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="ptolemy.domains.pn.kernel.PNDirector">
            <property name="id" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:directorclass:2:1">
            </property>
        </property>
        <property name="semanticType00" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:1:1#Director">
        </property>
        <property name="semanticType11" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:2:1#Director">
        </property>
        <property name="_location" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.Location" value="{90, 65}">
        </property>
    </property>
    <property name="derivedFrom" class="org.kepler.moml.NamedObjIdReferralList" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org/ns/:46142:69:14">
    </property>
    <property name="entityId" class="org.kepler.moml.NamedObjId" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org/ns/:46142:76:10">
    </property>
    <property name="Annotation2" class="ptolemy.vergil.kernel.attributes.TextAttribute">
        <property name="_hideName" class="ptolemy.data.expr.SingletonParameter" value="true">
        </property>
        <property name="_hideAllParameters" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="true">
        </property>
        <property name="textSize" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="14">
        </property>
        <property name="textColor" class="ptolemy.actor.gui.ColorAttribute" value="{0.0, 0.0, 1.0, 1.0}">
        </property>
        <property name="fontFamily" class="ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter" value="SansSerif">
        </property>
        <property name="bold" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="false">
        </property>
        <property name="italic" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="false">
        </property>
        <property name="anchor" class="ptolemy.data.expr.StringParameter" value="northwest">
        </property>
        <property name="text" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="This workflow shows how to use MultiInstanceComposite actor. This actor clones itself during execution.&#10;By building workflow using this actor, Distributor actor, and PN director, we can achieve parallel &#10;execution on one machine because the threads for the cloned actors can run in parallel.">
            <property name="_style" class="ptolemy.actor.gui.style.TextStyle">
                <property name="height" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="15">
                </property>
                <property name="width" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="40">
                </property>
            </property>
        </property>
        <property name="center" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="false">
        </property>
<property name="KeplerDocumentation" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.KeplerDocumentationAttribute">
<property name="description" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="author" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Edward A. Lee</configure></property>
<property name="version" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="userLevelDocumentation" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Use the Annotation attribute to annotate a workflow. Double-click the attribute to customize the content, font size, color, and basic formatting (bold and italics).</configure></property>
<property name="prop:fontFamily" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The font face. Select a font from the drop-down menu. The default is &quot;SansSerif&quot;.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:italic" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Select to indicate that the type should be italics. By default, type will not be italicized.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:bold" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Select to indicate that the type should be bold. By default, type will not be bold.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:textColor" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The font color. Specify a string representing an array of four elements: red, green, blue, and alpha, where alpha is transparency. The default is an opaque black, {0.0, 0.0, 0.0, 1.0}</configure></property>
<property name="prop:textSize" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The font size. Select an integer from the drop-down menu or specify a new size by typing it directly into the value field.  The default is 14.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:text" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The text of the annotation.</configure></property>
</property>        <property name="entityId" class="org.kepler.moml.NamedObjId" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org/ns/:46142:74:8">
        </property>
        <property name="class" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="ptolemy.vergil.kernel.attributes.TextAttribute">
            <property name="id" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:class:1199:1">
            </property>
        </property>
        <property name="semanticType00" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:1:1#DocumentationActor">
        </property>
        <property name="semanticType11" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:2:1#WorkflowDocumentation">
        </property>
        <property name="_location" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.Location" value="[-60.0, 335.0]">
        </property>
        <property name="derivedFrom" class="org.kepler.moml.NamedObjIdReferralList" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:actor:436:1:urn:lsid:kepler-project.org/ns/:9413:102:1:urn:lsid:kepler-project.org/ns/:12818:238:1:urn:lsid:kepler-project.org/ns/:40633:1184:3">
        </property>
    </property>
    <entity name="MultiInstanceComposite" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.hoc.MultiInstanceComposite">
        <property name="nInstances" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="5">
        </property>
        <property name="showClones" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="true">
        </property>
        <property name="_location" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.Location" value="[260.0, 165.0]">
        </property>
        <property name="SDF Director" class="ptolemy.domains.sdf.kernel.SDFDirector">
            <property name="iterations" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="0">
            </property>
            <property name="vectorizationFactor" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="1">
            </property>
            <property name="allowDisconnectedGraphs" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="false">
            </property>
            <property name="allowRateChanges" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="false">
            </property>
            <property name="constrainBufferSizes" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="true">
            </property>
            <property name="period" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="0.0">
            </property>
            <property name="synchronizeToRealTime" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="false">
            </property>
            <property name="Scheduler" class="ptolemy.domains.sdf.kernel.SDFScheduler">
                <property name="constrainBufferSizes" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="constrainBufferSizes">
                </property>
            </property>
<property name="KeplerDocumentation" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.KeplerDocumentationAttribute">
<property name="description" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="author" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Steve Neuendorffer</configure></property>
<property name="version" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="userLevelDocumentation" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>&#10;&lt;p&gt;The SDF Director is often used to oversee fairly simple, sequential workflows in which the director can determine the order of actor invocation from the workflow. Types of workflows that would run well under an SDF Director include processing and reformatting tabular data, converting one data type to another, and reading and plotting a series of data points. A workflow in which an image is read, processed (rotated, scaled, clipped, filtered, etc.), and then displayed, is also an example of a sequential workflow that requires a director simply to ensure that each actor fires in the proper order (i.e., that each actor executes only after it receives its required inputs).&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The SDF Director is very efficient and will not tax system resources with overhead. However, this efficiency requires that certain conditions be met, namely that the data consumption and production rate of each actor in an SDF workflow be constant and declared. If an actor reads one piece of data and calculates and outputs a single result, it must always read and output a single token of data. This data rate cannot change during workflow execution and, in general, workflows that require dynamic scheduling and/or flow control cannot use this director. Additionally, the SDF Director has no understanding of passing time (at least by default), and actors that depend on a notion of time may not work as expected. For example, a TimedPlotter actor will plot all values at time zero when used in SDF. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;By default, the SDF Director requires that all actors in its workflow be connected. Otherwise, the director cannot account for concurrency between disconnected workflow parts. Usually, a PN Director should be used for workflows that contain disconnected actors; however, the SDF Director's allowDisconnectedGraphs parameter may also be set to true. The SDF Director will then schedule each disconnected &quot;island&quot; independently. The director cannot infer the sequential relationship between disconnected actors (i.e., nothing forces the director to finish executing all actors on one island before firing actors on another). However, the order of execution within each island should be correct. Usually, disconnected graphs in an SDF model indicate an error.&lt;/p&gt;&#10; &#10;&lt;p&gt;Because SDF Directors schedule actors to fire only after they receive their inputs, workflows that require loops (feeding an actor's output back into its input port for further processing) can cause &quot;deadlock&quot; errors. The deadlock errors occur because the actor depends on its own output value as an initial input. To fix this problem, use a SampleDelay actor to generate and inject an initial input value into the workflow.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The SDF Director determines the order in which actors execute and how many times each actor needs to be fired to complete a single iteration of the workflow. This schedule is calculated BEFORE the director begins to iterate the workflow. Because the SDF Director calculates a schedule in advance, it is quite efficient. However, SDF workflows must be static. In other words, the same number of tokens must be consumed/produced at every iteration of the workflow. Workflows that require dynamic control structures, such as a BooleanSwitch actor that sends output on one of two ports depending on the value of a 'control', cannot be used with an SDF Director because the number of tokens on each output can change for each execution.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise specified, the SDF Director assumes that each actor consumes and produces exactly one token per channel on each firing. Actors that do not follow the one-token-per-channel firing convention (e.g., Repeat or Ramp) must declare the number of tokens they produce or consume via the appropriate parameters. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The number of times a workflow is iterated is controlled by the director's iterations parameter. By default, this parameter is set to &quot;0&quot;. Note that &quot;0&quot; does not mean &quot;no iterations.&quot; Rather, &quot;0&quot; means that the workflow will iterate forever. Values greater than zero specify the actual number of times the director should execute the entire workflow. A value of 1, meaning that the director will run the workflow once, is often the best setting when building an SDF workflow. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The amount of data processed by an SDF workflow is a function of both the number of times the workflow iterates and the value of the director's vectorizationFactor parameter. The vectorizationFactor is used to increase the efficiency of a workflow by increasing the number of times actors fire each time the workflow iterates. If the parameter is set to a positive integer (other than 1), the director will fire each actor the specified number of times more than normal. The default is 1, indicating that no vectorization should be performed. Keep in mind that changing the vectorizationFactor parameter changes the meaning of a nested SDF workflow and may cause deadlock in a workflow that uses it. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The SDF Director has several advanced parameters that are generally only relevant when an SDF workflow contains composite components. In most cases the period, timeResolution, synchronizeToRealTime, allowRateChanges, timeResolution, and constrainBufferSizes parameters can be left at their default values.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;For more information about the SDF Director, see the Ptolemy documentation (http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/papers/05/ptIIdesign3-domains/ptIIdesign3-domains.pdf).&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;</configure></property>
<property name="prop:allowDisconnectedGraphs" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Specify whether to allow disconnected actors in the workflow (by default, all actors are required to be connected). If disconnected actors are permitted, the SDF Director will schedule each disconnected 'island' independently. Nothing &quot;forces&quot; the director to finish executing all actors on one island before firing actors on another. However, the order of execution within each island should be correct. Usually, disconnected graphs in an SDF workflow indicate an error.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:allowRateChanges" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Specify whether dynamic rate changes are permitted or not. By default, rate changes are not permitted, and the director will perform a check to disallow such workflows. If the parameter is selected, then workflows that require rate parameters to be modified during execution are valid, and the SDF Director will dynamically compute a new schedule at runtime. This is an advanced parameter that can usually be left at its default value.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:constrainBufferSizes" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Specify whether buffer sizes are fixed. By default, buffers are fixed, and attempts to write to the buffer that cause the buffer to exceed its scheduled size result in an error. This is an advanced parameter that can usually be left at its default value.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:timeResolution" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The time precision used by this director. All time values are rounded to the nearest multiple of this number. The value is a double that defaults to &quot;1E-10&quot; (which is 10-10). This is an advanced parameter that can usually be left at its default value.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:iterations" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Specify the number of times a workflow is iterated. By default, this parameter is set to &quot;0&quot;. Note that &quot;0&quot; does not mean &quot;no iterations.&quot; Rather, &quot;0&quot; means that the workflow will iterate forever. Values greater than zero specify the actual number of times the director should execute the entire workflow. A value of 1, meaning that the director will run the workflow once, is often the best setting when building an SDF workflow. </configure></property>
<property name="prop:vectorizationFactor" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The vectorizationFactor is used to increase the efficiency of a workflow by increasing the number of times actors fire each time the workflow iterates. If the parameter is set to a positive integer (other than 1), the director will fire each actor the specified number of times more than normal. The default is 1, indicating that no vectorization should be performed. Keep in mind that changing the vectorizationFactor parameter changes the meaning of a nested SDF workflow and may cause deadlock in a workflow that uses it. </configure></property>
<property name="prop:synchronizeToRealTime" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Specify whether the execution should synchronize to real time or not. By default, the director does not synchronize to real time. If synchronize is selected, the director will only process the workflow when elapsed real time matches the product of the period parameter and the iteration count. Note: if the period parameter has a value of 0.0 (the default), then selecting this parameter has no effect. This is an advanced parameter that can usually be left at its default value.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:period" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The time period of each iteration. The value is a double that defaults to 0.0, which means that the director does not increment workflow time. If the value greater than 0.0, the actor will increment workflow time each time it fires. This is an advanced parameter that can usually be left at its default value. </configure></property>
</property>            <property name="entityId" class="org.kepler.moml.NamedObjId" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:director:1:1">
            </property>
            <property name="class" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="ptolemy.domains.sdf.kernel.SDFDirector">
                <property name="id" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:directorclass:1:1">
                </property>
            </property>
            <property name="semanticType00" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:1:1#Director">
            </property>
            <property name="semanticType11" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:2:1#Director">
            </property>
            <property name="_location" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.Location" value="[65.0, 75.0]">
            </property>
        </property>
        <property name="_windowProperties" class="ptolemy.actor.gui.WindowPropertiesAttribute" value="{bounds={278, 47, 879, 812}, maximized=false}">
        </property>
        <property name="_vergilSize" class="ptolemy.actor.gui.SizeAttribute" value="[600, 681]">
        </property>
        <property name="_vergilZoomFactor" class="ptolemy.data.expr.ExpertParameter" value="1.0">
        </property>
        <property name="_vergilCenter" class="ptolemy.data.expr.ExpertParameter" value="{300.0, 340.5}">
        </property>
<property name="KeplerDocumentation" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.KeplerDocumentationAttribute">
<property name="description" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="author" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Zoltan Kemenczy, Sean Simmons, Research In Motion Limited</configure></property>
<property name="version" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>$Id: MultiInstanceComposite.java 65768 2013-03-07 03:33:00Z cxh $</configure></property>
<property name="userLevelDocumentation" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>&#10;A {@link ptolemy.actor.TypedCompositeActor} that creates multiple&#10; instances of itself during the preinitialize phase of model execution.&lt;p&gt;&#10;&#10; A MultiInstanceComposite actor may be used to instantiate {@link&#10; #nInstances} identical processing blocks within a model. This actor&#10; (the &quot;master&quot;) creates {@link #nInstances}&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;1 additional&#10; instances (clones) of itself during the {@link #preinitialize()} phase&#10; of model execution and destroys these additional instances during model&#10; {@link #wrapup()}. MultiInstanceComposite &lt;em&gt;must be opaque&lt;/em&gt; (have&#10; a director), so that its Actor interface methods (preinitialize(), ...,&#10; wrapup()) are invoked during model initialization. Each instance may&#10; refer to its {@link #instance} [0..{@link #nInstances}-1] parameter&#10; which is set automatically by the master if it needs to know its&#10; instance number.&lt;p&gt;&#10;&#10; MultiInstanceComposite &lt;em&gt;input&lt;/em&gt; ports must not be multiports (for&#10; now) and may be connected to multiports or regular ports.  During&#10; preinitialize(), the master MultiInstanceComposite determines how its&#10; input ports are connected, and creates additional relations in its&#10; container (the model it is embedded in) to connect the input ports of&#10; its clones (instances) to the same output port if that port is a&#10; multiport.  If that output port is a regular port, the clone's input&#10; port is linked to the already existing relation between that output&#10; port and the master's input port.  MultiInstanceComposite&#10; &lt;em&gt;output&lt;/em&gt; ports must not be multiports (for now) and must be&#10; connected to input multiports. The master MultiInstanceComposite&#10; creates additional relations to connect the output ports of its clones&#10; to the input port. Finally, after all these connections are made, the&#10; master's preinitialize() calls preinitialize() of the clones.&lt;p&gt;&#10;&#10; From here on until wrapup(), nothing special happens. Type resolution&#10; occurs on all instances in the modified model, so does initialize() and&#10; the computation of schedules by directors of the master and clones.&lt;p&gt;&#10;&#10; During model wrapup(), the master MultiContextComposite deletes any&#10; relations created, unlinks any ports if needed, and deletes the clones&#10; it created. To re-synchronize vergil's model graph, an empty&#10; ChangeRequest is also queued with the Manager.&lt;p&gt;&#10;&#10; Actor parameters inside MultiInstanceComposite may refer to parameters&#10; of the container model. This presents a problem during cloning() and&#10; wrapup() where the container model's parameters are not in scope during&#10; the clone's validateSettables() (unless the MultiInstanceComposite is&#10; built as a moml class having its own set of parameters). This problem&#10; is for now solved by providing a temporary scope copy using a&#10; ScopeExtendingAttribute for the cloning() and wrapup() phases of the&#10; clones.&lt;p&gt;</configure></property>
<property name="prop:instance" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The index of this instance.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:showClones" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>If true, show the clones.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:nInstances" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The total number of instances to instantiate including instance 0 (the master copy).</configure></property>
</property>        <property name="" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.DocAttribute">
            <property name="description" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="&#10;A {@link ptolemy.actor.TypedCompositeActor} that creates multiple&#10; instances of itself during the preinitialize phase of model execution.&lt;p&gt;&#10;&#10; A MultiInstanceComposite actor may be used to instantiate {@link&#10; #nInstances} identical processing blocks within a model. This actor&#10; (the &quot;master&quot;) creates {@link #nInstances}&amp;nbsp;-&amp;nbsp;1 additional&#10; instances (clones) of itself during the {@link #preinitialize()} phase&#10; of model execution and destroys these additional instances during model&#10; {@link #wrapup()}. MultiInstanceComposite &lt;em&gt;must be opaque&lt;/em&gt; (have&#10; a director), so that its Actor interface methods (preinitialize(), ...,&#10; wrapup()) are invoked during model initialization. Each instance may&#10; refer to its {@link #instance} [0..{@link #nInstances}-1] parameter&#10; which is set automatically by the master if it needs to know its&#10; instance number.&lt;p&gt;&#10;&#10; MultiInstanceComposite &lt;em&gt;input&lt;/em&gt; ports must not be multiports (for&#10; now) and may be connected to multiports or regular ports.  During&#10; preinitialize(), the master MultiInstanceComposite determines how its&#10; input ports are connected, and creates additional relations in its&#10; container (the model it is embedded in) to connect the input ports of&#10; its clones (instances) to the same output port if that port is a&#10; multiport.  If that output port is a regular port, the clone's input&#10; port is linked to the already existing relation between that output&#10; port and the master's input port.  MultiInstanceComposite&#10; &lt;em&gt;output&lt;/em&gt; ports must not be multiports (for now) and must be&#10; connected to input multiports. The master MultiInstanceComposite&#10; creates additional relations to connect the output ports of its clones&#10; to the input port. Finally, after all these connections are made, the&#10; master's preinitialize() calls preinitialize() of the clones.&lt;p&gt;&#10;&#10; From here on until wrapup(), nothing special happens. Type resolution&#10; occurs on all instances in the modified model, so does initialize() and&#10; the computation of schedules by directors of the master and clones.&lt;p&gt;&#10;&#10; During model wrapup(), the master MultiContextComposite deletes any&#10; relations created, unlinks any ports if needed, and deletes the clones&#10; it created. To re-synchronize vergil's model graph, an empty&#10; ChangeRequest is also queued with the Manager.&lt;p&gt;&#10;&#10; Actor parameters inside MultiInstanceComposite may refer to parameters&#10; of the container model. This presents a problem during cloning() and&#10; wrapup() where the container model's parameters are not in scope during&#10; the clone's validateSettables() (unless the MultiInstanceComposite is&#10; built as a moml class having its own set of parameters). This problem&#10; is for now solved by providing a temporary scope copy using a&#10; ScopeExtendingAttribute for the cloning() and wrapup() phases of the&#10; clones.&lt;p&gt;">
            </property>
            <property name="author" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="Zoltan Kemenczy, Sean Simmons, Research In Motion Limited">
            </property>
            <property name="version" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="$Id: MultiInstanceComposite.java 65768 2013-03-07 03:33:00Z cxh $">
            </property>
            <property name="nInstances (parameter)" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="The total number of instances to instantiate including instance 0 (the master copy).">
            </property>
            <property name="instance (parameter)" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="The index of this instance.">
            </property>
            <property name="showClones (parameter)" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="If true, show the clones.">
            </property>
        </property>
        <port name="in" class="ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort">
            <property name="input"/>
            <property name="_location" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.Location" value="[110.0, 220.0]">
            </property>
        </port>
        <port name="out" class="ptolemy.actor.TypedIOPort">
            <property name="output"/>
            <property name="_location" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.Location" value="[430.0, 220.0]">
            </property>
        </port>
        <relation name="relation" class="ptolemy.actor.TypedIORelation">
            <property name="width" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="1">
            </property>
        </relation>
        <link port="in" relation="relation"/>
        <link port="out" relation="relation"/>
    </entity>
    <entity name="Ramp" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.Ramp">
        <property name="NONE" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="0">
        </property>
        <property name="init" class="ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter" value="0">
        </property>
        <property name="step" class="ptolemy.actor.parameters.PortParameter" value="1">
        </property>
        <property name="firingCountLimit" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="100">
        </property>
<property name="KeplerDocumentation" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.KeplerDocumentationAttribute">
<property name="description" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="author" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Yuhong Xiong, Edward A. Lee</configure></property>
<property name="version" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="userLevelDocumentation" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>&lt;p&gt;The Ramp actor is the equivalent of the &quot;for loop&quot; in many traditional computer languages. Its parameters include an intial value, the amount the value is incremented each time the actor fires (the 'step'), and the upper limit of the value (the firingCountLimit). The actor outputs an integer each time it is fired. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The actor's output can be used as a counter (increasing or decreasing), or as a parameter used in an incremented workflow. For example, the output of a Ramp actor can be input to an Expression actor to create file names that are unique for each iteration (e.g., 'file1', 'file2', etc.) The Ramp actor is also particularly useful with PN directed workflows where there is no way to set the number of iterations as a Director parameter. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The first time the actor fires, it outputs the value of its init parameter. The increment value, specified with either the step port or parameter, will only be added on the following iteration. To add an increment to the first iteration, use the Accumulator actor.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;The actor accepts values of any type that support addition.&lt;/p&gt;</configure></property>
<property name="port:output" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An output port that broadcasts the incremented value.</configure></property>
<property name="port:trigger" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An input port that has no declared type (in other words, the port can accept any data type: double, int, array, etc.) If the port is connected, the actor will not fire until the trigger port receives an input token. Connecting the port is optional, but useful when scheduling the actor to perform at a certain time.</configure></property>
<property name="port:step" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An input port that accepts the amount by which the output is incremented on each iteration. The port accepts a value of any type that supports addition. The value is an integer and defaults to 1.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:firingCountLimit" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The number of iterations that transpire before the actor indicates that it is finished. If firingCountLimit is set to zero, the actor has no limit imposed.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:step" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The amount by which the output is incremented on each iteration. The port accepts a value of any type that supports addition. The default is the integer 1.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:init" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The value produced by the Ramp on its first iteration. The default value is the integer 0.</configure></property>
</property>        <property name="entityId" class="org.kepler.moml.NamedObjId" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:actor:5:1">
        </property>
        <property name="class" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="ptolemy.actor.lib.Ramp">
            <property name="id" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:class:881:1">
            </property>
        </property>
        <property name="semanticType00" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:1:1#IterativeMathOperationActor">
        </property>
        <property name="semanticType11" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:2:1#IterativeOperation">
        </property>
        <property name="semanticType22" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:2:1#WorkflowInput">
        </property>
        <property name="_location" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.Location" value="[50.0, 165.0]">
        </property>
    </entity>
    <entity name="Distributor" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.Distributor">
        <property name="blockSize" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="1">
        </property>
<property name="KeplerDocumentation" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.KeplerDocumentationAttribute">
<property name="description" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="author" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Mudit Goel, Edward A. Lee</configure></property>
<property name="version" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="userLevelDocumentation" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>&lt;p&gt;&#10;A polymorphic distributor, which splits an input stream into a set of&#10;output streams. The distributor has an input port and an output port,&#10;the latter of which is a multiport.&#10;The types of the ports are undeclared and will be resolved by the type&#10;resolution mechanism, with the constraint that the output type must be&#10;greater than or equal to the input type. On each call to the fire method, the&#10;actor reads at most &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt; tokens from the input, where &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt; is&#10;the width of the output port times the &lt;i&gt;blockSize&lt;/i&gt; parameter,&#10;and writes &lt;i&gt;blockSize&lt;/i&gt; tokens to each output channel,&#10;in the order of the channels.  If there are fewer than &lt;i&gt;N&lt;/i&gt; tokens&#10;at the input, then the all available input tokens are sent to the output&#10;channels, and the fire() method returns.  In the next iteration of this&#10;actor, it will begin producing outputs on the first channel that did&#10;not have enough tokens in the previous iteration.&#10;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&#10;For the benefit of domains like SDF, which need to know the token consumption&#10;or production rate for all ports before they can construct a firing schedule,&#10;this actor sets the tokenConsumptionRate parameter for the input port&#10;to equal the number of output channels times the &lt;i&gt;blockSize&lt;/i&gt; parameter,&#10;and the output production rate is set to the &lt;i&gt;blockSize&lt;/i&gt; parameter.&#10;The consumption rate parameter is set each time that a link is established with&#10;the input port, or when a link is removed.  The director is notified&#10;that the schedule is invalid, so that if the link is modified at&#10;run time, the schedule will be recalculated if necessary.&#10;&lt;/p&gt;&#10;      </configure></property>
<property name="port:output" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>&#10;    </configure></property>
<property name="port:input" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>&#10;    </configure></property>
<property name="prop:blockSize" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>&#10;The number of tokens produced on each output channel on each firing. This is an &#10;integer with default value 1.&#10;    </configure></property>
</property>        <property name="entityId" class="org.kepler.moml.NamedObjId" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:actor:531:1">
        </property>
        <property name="class" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="ptolemy.actor.lib.Distributor">
            <property name="id" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="null">
            </property>
        </property>
        <property name="semanticType11" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:2:1#WorkflowControl">
        </property>
        <property name="_location" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.Location" value="[140.0, 165.0]">
        </property>
    </entity>
    <entity name="Display" class="ptolemy.actor.lib.gui.Display">
        <property name="_windowProperties" class="ptolemy.actor.gui.WindowPropertiesAttribute" value="{bounds={549, 328, 326, 208}, maximized=false}">
        </property>
        <property name="_paneSize" class="ptolemy.actor.gui.SizeAttribute" value="[326, 186]">
        </property>
        <property name="rowsDisplayed" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="10">
        </property>
        <property name="columnsDisplayed" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="40">
        </property>
        <property name="suppressBlankLines" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="false">
        </property>
<property name="KeplerDocumentation" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.KeplerDocumentationAttribute">
<property name="description" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="author" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Yuhong Xiong, Edward A. Lee</configure></property>
<property name="version" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="userLevelDocumentation" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>&lt;p&gt;The Display actor reads tokens of any type via its input multiport, and displays each token on a separate line in a text display window.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Specify the size of the text display window with the rowsDisplayed and columnsDisplayed parameters. Simply resizing the window onscreen does not persistently change the size when the workflow is saved, closed, and then re-opened. &lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;If the input is a string token, then the actor strips the surrounding quotation marks before displaying the value.&lt;/p&gt; &#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Select the suppressBlankLines parameter to specify that the actor not add blank lines to the display. By default, the actor will add blank lines.&lt;/p&gt;&#10;&#10;&lt;p&gt;Note: this actor can consume large amounts of memory. It is not advisable to use it to display large output streams.&lt;/p&gt;</configure></property>
<property name="port:input" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>A multiport that accepts tokens of any type.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:suppressBlankLines" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Specify whether the actor should display blank lines (the default) or suppress them.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:rowsDisplayed" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The vertical size of the display, in rows. The value is an integer that defaults to 10.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:columnsDisplayed" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The horizontal size of the display, in columns. The value is an integer that defaults to 40.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:title" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The title of the text display window. If specified, the value will appear in the title bar of the text display window.</configure></property>
</property>        <property name="entityId" class="org.kepler.moml.NamedObjId" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:actor:7:1">
        </property>
        <property name="class" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="ptolemy.actor.lib.gui.Display">
            <property name="id" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:class:883:1">
            </property>
        </property>
        <property name="semanticType00" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:1:1#TextualOutputActor">
        </property>
        <property name="semanticType11" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:2:1#TextualOutput">
        </property>
        <property name="_location" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.Location" value="{465.0, 185.0}">
        </property>
    </entity>
    <relation name="relation2" class="ptolemy.actor.TypedIORelation">
        <property name="width" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="1">
        </property>
    </relation>
    <relation name="relation" class="ptolemy.actor.TypedIORelation">
        <property name="width" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="1">
        </property>
    </relation>
    <relation name="relation3" class="ptolemy.actor.TypedIORelation">
        <property name="width" class="ptolemy.data.expr.Parameter" value="1">
        </property>
    </relation>
    <link port="MultiInstanceComposite.in" relation="relation2"/>
    <link port="MultiInstanceComposite.out" relation="relation3"/>
    <link port="Ramp.output" relation="relation"/>
    <link port="Distributor.input" relation="relation"/>
    <link port="Distributor.output" relation="relation2"/>
    <link port="Display.input" relation="relation3"/>
</entity>
